businessday.ng 2019-06-13

# Privacy Policy - Businessday NG

**Privacy Policy and Terms of Use**

BusinessDay together with its affiliate brands (BusinessDay Research and Intelligence Unit and BusinessDay Conferences & Events) takes your privacy seriously. We’ve laid out our GDPR compliant policy to serve you better and keep you in control over the information you allow us to collect. Our privacy policy may change so we recommend you check back on this page so you can always understand what your rights are.

**1\. What’s in this policy?**

This policy tells you:

* What information we might collect about you

* How we might use that information

* When we might use your details to contact you

* What information of yours we might share with others

* Your control over personal information you give us

2.  **What does this policy cover?**

This policy covers the services that are offered by BusinessDay well as other services provided under the BusinessDay brand including BusinessDay Research and Intelligence Unit and BusinessDay Conferences & Events and social media pages.

What’s not covered in this policy?

Content found on BusinessDay sometimes contains links to services run by other companies. Those companies will likely have their own privacy and cookies policies, so please keep in mind that our privacy policy only governs your data on our digital properties. Once you leave BusinessDay’s online property the information you give will govern their rules, not ours.

**How do you protect my personal information?**

We’re committed to keeping your information safe and we keep this at the center of our design process. We are constantly evaluating the best options available to media companies when it comes to guaranteeing the safety of our most important stakeholders, you.

That said, no service can be completely secure. If at any time, you feel your personal information is at risk, for example, a concern that someone got a hold of your password, you should contact us immediately. We’ll be happy to guide you through your options for changing your password.

**Where we store your information**

While our data centers are located in The United States for now, some of our partners or service providers may choose to host and process your information in a location outside of Nigeria. Security is a critical factor when we consider who we work with, Some companies that provide services to us run their services from outside Nigeria/the European Economic Area. We only let that happen if we are satisfied with their levels of security. Keep in mind that when you give us personal information it could be transferred, stored or processed in a location outside Nigeria/Africa/the EEA.

What types of personal information does BusinessDay collect about me?

Every time we ask for your personal information, we’ll give details about why we need it and how we’ll use it before you begin.

**1\. Information that you give to us**

Most frequently we will ask for information like Name, date of birth, and contact details. Occasionally, depending on what you’re signing up for, we may ask for other information. For example, if you’re signing up to receive an Election Newsletter we may ask you if you have your PVC. This will always be very clear.

1\. Device information

Devices include:

* Your computer

* Your mobile

* Your TV

* Your tablet

We automatically collect some technical information from these devices and web browsers even when you’re not signed into a BusinessDay account. This might include:

* IP (internet protocol) address

* Device ID

* App ID

**1\. Information on your activities outside BusinessDay when you talk about us**

An example such as BusinessDay being mentioned in a Twitter post, your Twitter handle will be collected.

What if I have a BusinessDay account?

When you register for a BusinessDay account or update your details or settings we ask for some personal information, like your email address and age. We also collect

information about how you use our services, as the articles you read and the programmes you subscribe to.

**5\. How long will BusinessDay keep my personal information?**

When you give us any personal information we’ll let you know how long we’ll hold it for. And always stick to these principles:

* We only hold your information for as long as we do the activities we told you about or have a valid reason to keep it.

* We think about what type of information it is, the amount collected, how sensitive it might be and any legal requirements.

* We design our services so that we don’t hold your information any longer than we have to

* We may close your BusinessDay account if you haven’t used it within a designated period of time. We’ll always send you an email to tell you that we plan to do this before we delete anything, so please check to see if we’ve sent you any emails about this.

**6\. How can BusinessDay use my personal information?**

We have to have a valid reason to use your personal information. It’s called the “lawful basis for processing“. Sometimes we might ask your permission to do things, like when you subscribe to an email. Other times, when you’d reasonably expect us to use your personal information, we don’t ask your permission, but only when:

* The law says it’s fine to use it, and

* It fits with the rights you have.

**We use your information for these types of things:**

1\. To deliver our services and to provide you with information about the. b. To deal with your requests, complaints and enquiries. c. To personalize services and give you things more tailored to your tastes e. To show you relevant advertising on another company’s site. f. To help us understand what kind of services you might use

And sometimes how you might share things with other people.

1\. To recommend things we think might interest you h. To show you advertising when you access a BusinessDay service from outside Nigeria

Some of this advertising might be tailored to you.

1\. To research and innovate

We learn from you daily and knowing how you use our services could help us build better products for you.

1\. To contact you about various things

2\. When will BusinessDay use my information to contact me?

We might use your information to contact you about different things, like:

* To update you on any changes to the BusinessDay’s policies, practices.

* To check with you about any service or activity you’ve signed up for.

* To contact you about a news tip or creative you sent us.

* To answer you when you’ve contacted us, or to respond to a comment or complaint.

* To invite you to take part in surveys about BusinessDay services, which are always voluntary.

* For marketing purposes.

* To send you notification of events or new products you might enjoy.

We’ll only contact you when we need to or when you’ve given us permission.

We’ll never contact you to ask for your BusinessDay account password.

**8\. Will I be contacted for marketing purposes?**

If you’re a subscriber you’ll receive a regular morning and evening brief of the news and top stories. If you’ve transacted with BusinessDay in recent times you may occasionally receive a reminder about how you can help support our journalistic mission by paying for a subscription. Other than on those occasions, we’ll only send you marketing emails or contact you about BusinessDay programmes, services and your views on issues about the BusinessDay if you’ve agreed to this.

Keep in mind, even if you unsubscribe, we may still contact you.

Will my personal information be used when BusinessDay advertises with other companies?

If you have a BusinessDay account we might use information that we hold about you to show you relevant and “targeted advertising” through other companies’ sites, like Facebook, Google, Snapchat or Twitter for example. This could be showing you a BusinessDay advertising message where we know you have a BusinessDay account and have used BusinessDay services.

If you don’t want to see our targeted advertising, you can set ad preferences in your social media companies’ settings. Also, you can visit your BusinessDay account and turn off personalization, but it will also turn off all personalized services.

**9\. When does BusinessDay share my personal information with others?**

We’ll never sell your personal information. We do share it with others in these ways:

1\. When you make something public

Like post a comment which the public can see.

1\. When we use other companies to power our services

In order for us to give you quality experiences and to understand how you’re using our services we often use other companies to process your personal information on our behalf. For example, sending you emails about things we think might interest you, or to ask you what you think about our services.

We make sure that your personal information is looked after as if we were handling it directly. We carefully select these companies, only share with them what they need to do the work and we make sure they keep your information secure.

1\. When we share personal information with companies in the BusinessDay family

2\. When you use another company’s service that connects to us, like voice-enabled devices

To access our services through a voice-enabled device, like Amazon Alexa, you need to connect your device to your BusinessDay account. We’ll share an identifier for your BusinessDay account with the voice service. It’s completely up to you if you want to use the BusinessDay in this way.

1\. When we do collaborative research

We do research activities and sometimes collaborate with research partners. Every now and then we share our content and data with them. This might include information we’ve collected about you. But we’re careful about what we share and what our research partners can do with it.

1\. Sometimes by law we have to pass on your information to other organisations

We might also share your information if we have to by law, or when we need to protect you or other people from harm.

10\. What’s different for kids and teens?

BusinessDay has services that are appropriate for all ages. Here’s what happens when you use them.

1\. Why do we collect information about you in the first place?

We keep information about you so that we can:

* Get the right services for you

* Plan and improve our services

* Keep in touch with you

1\. We’ll always tell you why we’re collecting your personal information

We’ll explain why and how we use it and for how long. It’s called a “privacy notice”. And if we need your parent or guardian’s permission we’ll give you clear details about what’s needed at the time.

1\. We can only use your personal information if we have a valid reason

2\. We share personal information about you to others but we follow some rules

The main rule is we never sell your personal information to anyone.

1\. We might ask you to tell us your age

To make sure you use parts of BusinessDay that are suitable for you. For example:

* So that adults don’t post comments on kid’s message boards

* when you want to get a BusinessDay account

1\. Sometimes we’ll ask to get your parent or guardian’s consent

You’ll see a notification. We might also ask for some details from them, so that we can contact them. Other times we may contact your parent or guardian:

* So you can get notifications from us

* So we can show you more things we think you’ll like, based on what you do

* So you can post comments

* So you can upload your contributions to us

1\. Sometimes we’ll tell your parents about your activities

For example, if you’re under 13 and your parent or legal guardian has asked to see every content you upload, we’ll share it with them before it goes public.

1\. When we contact you

Sometimes we’ll need to get in touch with you but we’ll always follow these rules.

1\. It’s safe to use us

It’s our job to keep your personal information safe and secure. That’s why we design our services with your safety in mind. And we’re always looking for the best ways to improve this.

There are also things that you can do to keep safe, like thinking about what information you share and how to keep your devices secure.

.

1\. You’re in control of how we use cookies and tracking

Cookies are bits of data that are stored on your device. Some things on our websites wouldn’t be able to work without these cookies. So they’re always on when you visit us.

We use cookies and tracking to make things easier for you, like remembering where you got to in a game or what emoji you selected.

You can switch off some cookies and similar tracking technologies. Or your parent or guardian can do this if you’re under 13.

1\. What we do when you post, upload or share a creation

When you share your creation with us we’ll try to tell you exactly what we’re going to do with it.

1\. You’ve got privacy rights, the same as adults, so get to know what they are

You can:

* ask us what personal information we hold about you

* ask us to correct or delete your personal information

* tell us to stop using your personal information

If you’re 13 or older, you can do this yourself, but not always.

Sometimes we’ll be asking for your parent or guardian to do that.

If you’re under 13 your parent or guardian probably has to do it for you.

**11\. Can I delete my information?**

This depends on what information you’re talking about.

1\. If you’re talking about a BusinessDay account

You can delete your account. You simply need to contact us and let us know you would like to delete your account and we will do so within 48hrs. Even when your account is deleted, please keep in mind:

* We keep a record of how you’ve used our services, but this information can’t be linked back to you.

* We also keep anything you’ve uploaded or commented on.

1\. What about other information I’ve shared with you?

We might have collected other personal information that you might ask to be deleted that has nothing to do with BusinessDay account.

**12\. What are my rights?**

Remember, you’re in control of your personal information.

You have the right to:

* Request a copy of your information.

* Not let robots make big decisions about you.

* To ask us to correct information that’s demonstrably wrong, to delete it or to request that we only use it for certain purposes.

* To change your mind, and ask us to stop using your information. For example, unsubscribing from any marketing emails.

Bear in mind, sometimes we might not be able to help. Like if the law tells us we can’t or it forms part of our journalistic output.

**13\. How does BusinessDay use cookies and similar tracking?**

**14\. What are cookies and tracking technologies?**

Cookies are bits of data which are stored in your computer or mobile when you visit a website or app.

There are also similar pieces of tracking information we collect.

1\. Why do we use cookies and other tracking?

To do a few different things:

* To remember information about you, so you don’t have to give it to us again. And again. And again.

* To keep you signed in, even on different devices

* To help us understand how people are using our services, so we can make them better

* To deliver advertising to websites outside of the Nigeria and Europe

* To help us personalise BusinessDay to you by remembering your preferences and settings. And your progress, so you can pause and pick up where you left off watching a programme, even on a different device

* To find out if our emails have been read and if you find them useful

A few things on our websites wouldn’t work without some cookies. Tech people call these “strictly necessary cookies”. They’re always on when you visit us.

But we want to use others like functional, performance and advertising cookies to make your experience more enjoyable. We’ll only use them if you’ve agreed. You can always change your mind.

Bear in mind there are some other cookies out there from other companies. These “third-party cookies” might track how you use different websites, including ours. For example, you might get a social media company’s cookie when you see the option to share something. You can turn them off, but not through us.

**1\. How long do cookies last?**

Some are erased when you close the browser on your website or app. Others stay longer, sometimes forever, and are saved onto your device so they’re there when you come back.

1\. How do I control my cookies and tracking?

When you first visit us, we’ll tell you about our cookies and ask you to agree if we can use them. You can always change your mind by going to your settings.

Stopping all cookies might mean you can’t access some BusinessDay services, or that some of them might not work properly for you.

Another way to control some tracking is in the settings on your device.

**14\. How will I find out about changes to this policy?**

We update this policy sometimes. If we make important changes, like how we use your personal information, we’ll let you know. It might be a notice, an email, or a message in your app.

If you don’t agree to the changes, then you can always stop using our services, delete your account and stop giving us any more personal information. We’d be sorry to see you go.

15\. How can I contact the BusinessDay? You can contact BusinessDay by sending an email to digital@businessdayonline.com
